<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
	<title>A muse, amuse</title>
	<description>I'm always amused and amusing you</description>		
	<link>http://localhost:4000</link>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	    
        <item>
        <title>The future, question mark</title>
    	        
		<description>&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a good blog post, but I suppose that doesn’t matter when there’s no one reading this except for myself and a serendipitious reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In complete honesty, there hasn’t been much going in my life. Moments have blurred: waking up, showering, sitting my ass down for ~8 hours, eating, tampering on my phone, then sleeping. Repeat this five times a week. The weekends come and go; they’re never long enough. I’m perpetually twiddling my thumbs for inspiration and motivation to hit me, so that I may finally create something extraordinary that may even surprise myself. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VoSoZyiHZ6o&quot;&gt;Sour times&lt;/a&gt;, indeed, that I measure my days by these pointless, trivial acts of humanhood. On the other hand, I have taken up fasted, morning runs only because I like losing weight (very important) and it helps with health (slightly important; we all die someday). Running, otherwise, is pretty awful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s my fault that my current life seems so meaningless. Don’t people say that real meaning is found within and not externally? Maybe there really is nothing inside me, only big empty. One thing that’s been whirling in my emptiness is how much unspoken responsibility that I will have in the future, especially with finances. With all this supposed free time, I could be learning this and that coding language, working on side projects, and reading tech books to prepare for a better job. Isn’t that what all of us want? A better job with a fatter salary? Each time I start a new project or learning plan, I lose all interest and motivation because I don’t care. I don’t care about my company. I don’t care about best styling practices. I don’t care about what language to choose for a specific task. I don’t care about learning about technical things. I don’t care about fixing flaky tests. I don’t really care about becoming a better developer. I wouldn’t care if our competitors outdid us. I. Don’t. Care. All it is to me is a paycheque; beyond this practical need, I wish I could enjoy my job like some of my other coworkers. If only I didn’t have debts I needed to owe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another bother of mine is that so many my hobbies have become digital, just spending so much time glued to my computer/laptop. Before COVSHIT happened, I wanted to make 2020 summer the best I had, so much that it would make up for many years of summers robbed by school. The promise of concerts, Wonderland, music lessons, carpentry workshops, foreign travel, and late summer nights out with friends was enough for me to forget how I unhappy I was at work. As long as I could indulge in these simple pleasures, I would be happy. Well, five months later, and here we are at an impasse. At least summer is here, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the arrival of spring and summer, some quarantine measures have been lifted and life seems to be moving as it always has in the past. The images of people walking and laughing with their friends, patrons on patios enjoying belated drinks and food, and ballers balling in the courts all paint a form of new normality that presents itself that it’s here to stay. While it is a season to celebrate and take advantage of longer days, I wonder how the people will react if and when the strict measures are placed upon us again after tasting an appetizer of quasi-normality. Will people easily comply as they did in March, or will it be met with resistance as shown in some parts of the States? Seeing people here enter indoor public spaces without masks gives me pause, especially in a time when wearing masks indoors is heavily encouraged and have shown to stop the spread of COVID. It is the selfishness of such people that welcomes me to my pessimism. Perhaps in the near future, I will be proven wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I’ll be proven wrong about everything I’ve blabbed about, because this isn’t the life I envisioned myself living. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;inb4 people poopoo me for complaining about the relatively cushy life I have: Yes, I recognize that I have immense privilege, but it does not negate the worries I have for myself and other important parties in the future. Everything can change so suddenly (for the worse) and that’s the scary part. Life seems daunting when I think hard about it. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
		<link>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/09/the-future.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/07/09/the-future.html</guid>
        </item>
	    
        <item>
        <title>Safety?</title>
    	        
		<description>&lt;p&gt;Is one of the defining features of womanhooe worrying for your personal safety, whether in or outside your home? Yes, it seems so, based on personal and other women’s experiences. As children, women are always told to be watchful, yielding, and quiet, especially to men. From an objective view, there &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; some truth to it; men have larger frames, thicker bones, greater physical strength, and testosterone, all of which can lead to a potent cocktail for (un)intentional violence. Women, on the other hand, are physically weaker than men. I don’t have to pull out research papers to know, on average, that this is true. Additionally, more men overwhelmingly commit violent crimes than women. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though these are all rational reasons to preach to naïve daughters who know nothing about the world, it is an enormous stain on society. Has society as a whole yet to evolve on the basic rights of women? The simple fact that women’s rights is deemed separately as &lt;strong&gt;women’s rights&lt;/strong&gt; instead of &lt;strong&gt;human rights&lt;/strong&gt; speaks volumes on how society views women as a whole. Not &lt;strong&gt;human rights&lt;/strong&gt;, because we’re not &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; considered human… and if so, only for the lecherous benefit for men. So, is it still confounding that society teaches women to live in perpetual fear and suspicion?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“DON’T DRESS LIKE A SLUT, BECAUSE YOU’LL GET RAPED” is something all women hear as children. Here, bodily autonomy is ignored for the comfort of violent, unstable men. Why should women give up their rights to their body just so they &lt;strong&gt;might&lt;/strong&gt; not get raped? Some men say they would love to be ogled by women (any, of course, that are young and attractive, of course…) and that they should appreciate the attention they get, but have they ever been in such a vulnerable position where they may contemplate the stupidity of their statement from a point of empathy and self-awareness? I’m afraid the answer is a resounding &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt;. From society’s response alone, men are allowed to be sluts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As seen in the links, men do commit violent crimes more often than women, though men are largely the victims in homicides, assaults, and muggings. Anything I have said above does not cancel how I feel about men’s safety. Everyone should feel and be safe, but the way we handle women’s victimizations makes no sense. Even if women do everything and do the opposite of everything they’ve been told not to do, it takes one act against them to break everything.  Be more intimidating. Don’t look at them. Walk away. It’s bullshit. As if walking away helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;https://www150.statcan.gc.ca/n1/pub/85f0033m/2010024/part-partie1-eng.htm#h2_6 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;https://ucr.fbi.gov/crime-in-the-u.s/2014/crime-in-the-u.s.-2014/persons-arrested/main &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Just posting those two links because I’m sure there’s some snivelly man who thinks I’m lying. Something something facts. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
		<link>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/19/safe.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/05/19/safe.html</guid>
        </item>
	    
        <item>
        <title>Loss</title>
    	        
		<description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is the four year anniversary of my friend’s passing. It’s something I’ve meticulously etched into my mind, because it’s the least I can do for being a subpar friend. April 14th, 2016. Avril 14th. Same date, same pain. &lt;br /&gt;
I know exactly why they left, but I still have a lot of questions that will remain unanswered. Some have been answered after doing some inspector work, and sometimes I wish I never found her journal. I’d be a liar if I said I didn’t notice she needed more help than she got, because I did notice, but I didn’t know how to broach the topic or help. After four years of painful contemplation, I realized help doesn’t mean you escort them to their therapy sessions or make sure they’re taking their medication. Sometimes, it’s about the simple gestures that make them feel less alone. Reaching out to them everyday and speaking with them like you did before they got really sick, but being mindful of their conditions, is one thing that helps to fend off loneliness. Inviting them over to your place is also a better way than just texting or videochatting, since you can physically connect. Seeing and hearing the subtle changes in their expressions and tones and acting accordingly to accommodate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difficult part for me was not listening to the unsure voices in my head that told me otherwise. If they want to talk to you, they would reach out. Give them space. It’s too awkward anyway, what the hell do you know about what they’re going through? It’s not like they’ll do anything anyway, so just wait it out until they reach out. You’re really busy, so they’ll understand if you can’t talk that much. With this, I fell into a pit of excuses while I pushed my conscience away. If you can’t think about it, then you don’t have to deal with it. They’ll come to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come to me, they did, not with good news, but bad news. A wake at night, then a funeral in the morning. It was all so fast, and I couldn’t look at anyone in the eyes. I liked how your mom was honest about your cause of death instead of shrinking away to appease those who can’t handle heavy topics. I still remember how little of our high school friends showed up and how you would have liked the quartet playing in remembrance of you. I couldn’t believe that you were gone. We talked about this before, in hypotheticals; we talked about all the details and nooks and crannies. Just a few months back, we were talking about your funeral and how you wanted me to disallow a certain someone from attending your funeral. I felt like I betrayed you when that person came to your wake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I wish I had said something. Not just to that specific person, but to almost all the people that came. How dare do people come to say their respects as a friend when you didn’t treat them nicely when they were alive? Who gave you permission? Your guilt? There was a lot of anger I swallowed because I was just as guilty as them. I might have been one of the few whom she regularly (underestimation) talked with, but I was closer to her, which meant I had more responsibility. In that sense, wasn’t I guiltier than them? The anger I projected to others reflected back into my eyes. Instead of becoming blind like the sun usually does, I became too aware of the glare in its every detail. There was always someone or something I wanted to blame because it would have implied a definite sense of knowing, since knowledge gives you control based on what you know. Nothing is worse than silence. I also wanted to free myself of my personal guilt; I just wanted persmission to wash the blood off my hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been four years where I have managed to wash some blood off. Despite the cleanse, I was affected. It has made me bitter, untrusting, and lonely because people have shown that they don’t care as much as they say. Ironically, being one of those people showed me how I also wasn’t a great friend and how my actions (or inactions) indirectly ended in such tragedy. Self-hatred is a large, looming cloud that float every so often. It is not helping that I still have trouble going to their grave. It’s been two years since I’ve visited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is ultimately my lonely path that no one will truly understand. It’s just a matter of growing calluses and learning to walk properly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
		<link>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/13/loss.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/04/13/loss.html</guid>
        </item>
	    
        <item>
        <title>We are alone</title>
    	        
		<description>&lt;p&gt;In the time of a public health crisis, my city has been on an indefinte semi-lockdown for about three weeks, which has given me lots of unused time. See, when I was in school or was too busy to think about leisure activities, I always longed to watch a movie on my perpetually growing list. While I have already watched Roma in late December 2018, it left quite an impression on me. With its beautiful cinematography and subtle yet plot that captures the burdens of everyday life with quiet commentary of the classism, misogyny, and racial divides of 1970’s Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to thank the lockdown for giving me almost unlimited time to enjoy myself with movies, both visited and unvisited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, there will be a lot of spoilers, and no real unifying theme except to show the subtle symbolism with the blatant contrasts of this movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went into the theatres with friends not knowing what to expect; before entering the hall, all I had seen was the large poster, with its golden art deco font, decreeing ROMA, as a family embraced each other with palpable emotion on the beach. Alright, it looked good enough to spend 2 hours with each other, but I feel like it was more than just a way to pass the time. From what I can remember, it moved all of us that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roma begins with one of its most important symbols: water. Water cleanses, destroys, and nurtures. We see the actions of our silent protagonist, Cleo, a maid of well-to-do family in 1970’s Roma, a (now gentrified) middle-class neighbourhood in Mexico City. A new day begs for a clean slate, washed by soap and water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at the tones and textures of the floor: a mundane scene is turned beautiful by these two important factors, something that we see many times throughout (but is not discussed here, sorry).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-04-09-roma/cleanse.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;water&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cleo takes a small break with the family’s youngest, Pepe, where she pretends she is dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I like being dead.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Pepe pretends to die for fun, Cleo says this with a modicum of seriousness. What kind of troubles has she faced? At least in that moment, she is able to lie back and enjoy the gentle sun beaming down with the scent and sounds of everyday life. We are troubled, but it’s quickly dismissed; instead, we absorb the soft, gorgeous moments of serenity.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-04-09-roma/being.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;being&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nice houses, nice kids, and nice cars - it’s all superficial. Cleo and Pepe see the mother (Sofia) bid adieu to the father (Antonio), as he leaves for two weeks for a conference. From their tense body language, the audience knows the peace has been broken. Antonio is being embraced by his wife out of desperation, whereas Cleo hugs Pepe - simply because he lets her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-04-09-roma/embrace.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Water&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now… look at these. Cleo has been seeing a seemingly nice boy named Fermin, and in these moments, we feel uncomfortable at how intimate it is. Should we be witnessing their young, budding love? It feels like I’m violating their privacy. Nevertheless, I love how Cuarón framed the handholding scene, with Fermin in extreme focus and heavy contrast against the hotel background - Cuarón forcibly moves our chin and orders us: “Look”… and look we do. The way he holds her hands with such care and focus and how she smiles makes the audience believe that true love might actually exist.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-04-09-roma/intimacy.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Water&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-04-09-roma/intimacy2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Water&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But nah, true love doesn’t exist, at least not in this movie if we understand the dynamic between Sofia and Antonio. After missing her period, Cleo realizes she’s pregnant and tells Fermin at the smoky movie theatre, who promptly leaves with the perfect excuse of going to the washroom. (Hint: he never waits for her.) Upset at the prospect of being fired, Cleo confides in Sofia, who is more than happy for her and takes her to the hospital to confirm her pregnancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With New Years waiting, Sofia takes her family to her friend’s hacienda, where everyone drinks a bit too much and has a bit of fun, until “Fire!” is heard by all. Everyone scurries to put out the fire, running to fetch water, lining up to hand filled buckets; seemingly everyone has forgotten about the New Year. Enter the guy in a costume, who sings to ring in the New Year. Everyone forgets about him too, but he keeps singing - to appease whom? To me, an intense scene that shows the absurdity of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-04-09-roma/fire.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Water&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After returning from the hacienda, Cleo is determined to find Fermin, and she finds herself in an underdeveloped village outside of Mexico City - in the background, a political candidate campaigns that he will bring water here! She finds herself at a field where Fermin trains martial arts. A funny looking dude called the “Guru” demonstrates the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vriksasana&quot;&gt;vriksasana&lt;/a&gt; while blindfolded. Everyone laughs and expects something impossible to happen, but he shuts down everyone by asking them to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one’s laughing now. The bystanders and trainees all have a difficult time doing a seemingly easy task - but not Cleo. Despite her silent anguish, she is the only one capable of perfectly balancing, showing her quiet yet resilient strength.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-04-09-roma/balance.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;balance&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-04-09-roma/balanced.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;balance!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though Cleo is finally able to meet him, her quest is futile, as Fermin threatens to beat her and her child if she tries to see him again, then calling her a “servant bitch”. Defeated, she returns back to Mexico City, where later she encounters a very drunk Sofia. While Fermin is dismissive, Sofia understands Cleo with a careless embrace. They share a moment of solidarity as women who have lost significant others, mingled with a cold touch of reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We women are always alone.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are both alone in their struggles, yet understand each other perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-04-09-roma/alone.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time passes, and Cleo is nearly due, which means they need furniture for the baby. The abuelita takes Cleo to a shopping trip for the baby, and as they walk to the store from their car, they face a tense atmosphere of students with signs and soldiers on standby. It’s all very palpable and the audience is uneasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this isn’t a goddamn obvious metaphor for a ticking bomb to denote what will happen immediately, then I don’t know what is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-04-09-roma/clocks.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;clocks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within seconds of entering the store, the streets are in discord, with shots heard in the air, as people, both protesters and soldiers, are running around to escape or to attack. I don’t know much about Mexican history, but it is implied that the soldiers were &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/El_Halconazo#Los_Halcones&quot;&gt;Los Halcones&lt;/a&gt;, a government trained military group that were used to suppress protests during &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mexican_Dirty_War&quot;&gt;Mexico’s turbulent times&lt;/a&gt;. Two protestors barge into the store, desperate for some help, yet the soldiers find them and one of them is executed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an incredibly tense moment, where Cleo sees Fermin (!) again - this time, he has a gun. We think back to his threat before: will he kill Cleo and her child? After uncomfortable stares and seconds, he leaves with his group; everyone is safe yet Cleo’s water breaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes them two hours to get the hospital, and the pressure is building up, with the cries of babies and the astounding number of people waiting for treatment. While others wait in line, Cleo is able to get treatment as the family has ties to the hospital. As Cleo is taken to the emergency, abuelita is asked information about Cleo that she cannot answer. Cleo is taken for granted by the family, an object that cleans, cooks, and shops without a complaint. They know so much about us, but do we know anything about them? 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-04-09-roma/unknown.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;unknown&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The doctors do their best and Cleo crowns and gives birth - but no cries are heard. The baby is not breathing and after futile attempts of CPR, they announce to her that her baby is a girl. Everyone is sorry. 
Cleo mourns her baby’s life, as the doctors dress her child in a cool, clinical way, as if the baby was an object.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-04-09-roma/birthdeath.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;birthdeath&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sofia, noticing Cleo’s anguish, invites her to the family’s vacation to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tuxpan&quot;&gt;Tuxpan&lt;/a&gt;, hoping that it will clear her mind. Cleo reluctantly accepts the invitation.  And… off we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-04-09-roma/landscape.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;landscape&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mexico is gorgeous, isn’t it? Everything’s soft and of the same tone. The composition is well laid, giving  equal balance to the solemn sky and the desert, the clouds a foreboding warning of the things that might happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The children beg Sofia to swim at the beach before they go to their hotel, and she agrees. They are happy and bubbly rolling around in the sand and beach. After arriving at the hotel, the family sits down at a restaurant where Sofia breaks the news: the reason for the trip was so that Antonio can take his things without discomfort. She explains that while they are separated, daddy still loves them and that they’ll be closer than ever - including Cleo. The family shows their love for Cleo, who, despite looking uncomfortable, is receptive to their affections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s a big, sad family dinner without dessert to sweeten the misery? As everyone dejectedly eats their ice cream, there is a quiet moment as a couple takes their wedding photo, which suddenly breaks into energetic bursts of laughter and music. On one hand, there is a dissolution of a marriage and on the other, a formation of one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-04-09-roma/dissolution.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Water&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, the family packs to leave, but they decide to visit the beach once more where the waves are rougher than before. The children are warned not to go too deep as Sofia and Toño, her eldest son, leave to go to the store, but knowing children, they don’t listen. Cleo watches from the sand as they become smaller and smaller. While she cannot swim, she bravely faces the waves and saves them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, I was wondering if she would have done that for a stranger, as she cannot swim and have faced so much grief in the past. Why save a stranger who might not be grateful? Why do that if she might die? Seeing the glimpses of Cleo does make me think otherwise, that she would risk her life so that the other person might not suffer like her. She understands how hard it is to be alone and how isolating traumas can be, so she does what is right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Sofia and Toño return to Cleo and the crumpled children, they break down, embrace one another, and show their devotion to her. This is a moment of vulnerability of Cleo - after deciding to receive their love, she tells them what she could not tell anyone else, that she never wanted the baby, but also of the pain that lingered when her baby was stillborn. To feel conflicting emotions is a painful burden to bear and even more so to share it with a family who might not understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quiet drive back to Mexico City reveals their house to be reorganized - shelves gone, books on the ground, and rooms are switched around. The children are ecstatic about the new arrangement and have put the bad news in the back of their heads. It is time to rejoyce in the small, simple things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last moments of the movie, Cleo climbs the stairs to the roof to attend to her normal chores while a plane flies in the sky. Things seem to be looking up for Cleo; this pain too shall pass. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020-04-09-roma/skies.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Water&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
		<link>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/09/roma.html</link>
		<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/04/09/roma.html</guid>
        </item>
	    
</channel>
</rss>
